Finding Aid for Harold Titus Papers, 1908-1967
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Harold Titus Papers 1908-1967
Titus, Harold, 1888-1967.
5.2 linear ft.
86254 Aa 2
Traverse City, Michigan, free-lance writer and conservation editor of Field and Stream magazine; correspondence, manuscripts of writings, diaries, topical files, and photographs.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Mrs. Beth Titus (donor no. 4621 ), in 1968.
The collection is open to research.
Harold Titus was born February 20, 1888 in Traverse City, Michigan. He attended the University of Michigan, 1907-1911. While at school, Titus also worked as a reporter for the Detroit News (1907-1910). He then became a fruit grower in Grand Traverse County while also continuing to write novels and articles for conservation magazines. An ardent conservationist, Titus helped organize the Isaac Walton League in 1922. He was also a long-term member of the Michigan Conservation Commission, serving 1927-1935 and 1937-1949. He died October 9,1967.
The collection includes correspondence, manuscript articles, and conservation columns; materials collected by the Michigan Writers' Program concerning Michigan logging; also diaries, speeches, newspaper clippings, notebooks, genealogy, photographs, and miscellaneous material concerning Titus' interest in conservation, forestry, and fishing.
Subjects:
Authors, American--Michigan.; Conservation of natural resources--Michigan.; Field and stream.; Fishing--Michigan.; Forests and forestry--Michigan.; Journalists--Michigan--Traverse City.; Logging--Michigan.; Motion picture industry.; Natural resources--Michigan.; Titus, Harold, 1888-; Traverse City (Mich.); Writers' Program (Mich.)
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Agriculture--Michigan.; Business enterprises--Michigan--Muskegon.; Conservation of natural resources--Michigan.; Fish.; Hunting--Michigan.; Indians of North America--Michigan.; Kawbawgam, Charles, d. 1902.; Michigan. State Planning Commission.; Michigan State University.; Muskegon (Mich.)--Busiess enterprises.; Romney, George W., 1907-; Thayer Lumber Company.; Titus, Harold, 1888-; Women.
Genre Terms:
Diaries.; Photographs.
- Correspondence,1910-1967
  - 1910-1935, 22 folders (Box 1)
  - 1936-1967, 26 folders (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2)
- Writings, diaries, and speeches
  - Manuscript articles and columns, 22 folders (Box 3)
  - Manuscript articles and columns, 21 folders (Box 4)
  - Manuscript articles and columns, 11 folders (Box 5)
  - Diaries
    - 1954-1956 (Box 5)
    - Undated, of cowboy experience, with story ideas (Box 5)
    - Fragments (Box 5)
  - Speeches (Box 5)
- Topical file
  - Conservation (Box 5)
  - Fishing and wildlife (Box 5)
  - Forestry (Box 5)
  - Forestry Advisory Committee (Box 5)
  - Genealogy (Box 5)
  - Hunting (Box 5)
  - Land use (Box 5)
  - Titus Bros. orchard records (Box 5)
  - Williford, C.C. (TV weatherman) correspondence (Box 5)
- Other materials
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 5)
  - Notes, Miscellaneous (Box 5)
  - Scrapbook of Titus articles for Detroit News, 1908-1910, photocopy (Box 5)
  - Writers' Program source materials concerning Michigan logging, 4 folders (Box 5)
- Photographs
  - Agriculture (Box 6)
  - Fish planting (Box 6)
  - Hunting (Box 6)
  - Indians (Box 6)
  - Portraits (Box 6)
  - State Planning Commission (includes George Romney) (Box 6)
  - Stream improvement (Box 6)
  - Thayer Lumber Company (Box 6)